<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pi signaling on YiLab</title>
    <link>https://yilab.life/tags/pi-signaling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pi signaling on YiLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yilab.life/tags/pi-signaling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the code of plant central phosphate signaling</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2022tips/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2022tips/detail/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Phosphate (Pi) is involved in numerous metabolic processes and plays a vital role in plant growth. Green plants have evolved intricate molecular bases of Pi-signaling to maintain cellular Pi homeostasis. Here, we summarize recent advances in the molecular and structural bases of central Pi-signaling and discuss pending questions.
 Discovery of the core elements involved in P signaling
(A) Key studies uncovering the molecular and structural basis of P signaling machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plant Cell paper is online now!</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2022tpc/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2022tpc/detail/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Phosphate (Pi) limitation represents a primary constraint on crop production. To better cope with Pi deficiency stress, plants have evolved multiple adaptive mechanisms for phosphorus acquisition and utilization, including the alteration of growth and the activation of Pi starvation signaling. However, how these strategies are coordinated remains largely unknown. Here, we found that the alternative splicing (AS) of REGULATOR OF LEAF INCLINATION 1 (RLI1) in rice (Oryza sativa) produces two protein isoforms: RLI1a, containing MYB DNA binding domain; and RLI1b, containing both MYB and coiled-coil (CC) domains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
