<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on YiLab</title>
    <link>https://yilab.life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on YiLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yilab.life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Relevant Journals</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/links/journals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/links/journals/</guid>
      <description>Research Journals Multidisciplinary
 Cell Cell Reports Current Biology Developmental Cell Molecular Cell Nature Nature Biotechnology Nature Genetics Nature Communications Communications Biology Science Science Advances PNAS PLOS Biology BMC Biology Advanced Science eLife The EMBO Journal EMBO Reports Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Biology Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences National Science Review Science Bulletin Science China Life Sciences  Plants
 Nature Plants Molecular Plant The Plant Cell New Phytologist Plant Physiology The Plant Journal Plant, Cell &amp;amp; Environment Journal of Experimental Botany Journal of Integrative Plant Biology Plant Biotechnology Journal Plant Communications  Genetics and Genomics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Keke Yi</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/00_kekeyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/00_kekeyi/</guid>
      <description>I’m a group leader of soil-plant interaction at the Institute of Agricultural Resources and Regional Planning (IARRP) from the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences (CAAS). My group is working with the molecular mechanism of Pi uptake and homeostasis in plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/links/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/links/database/</guid>
      <description>* for recommended
 Genome  PLAZA* Phytozome* ONEKP* Ensembl Plants CoGe GDA - Genome Database for Angiosperms Fernbase Published Plant Genomes GreenPhylDB v5 PGSB - Plant Genome and Systems Biology MaizeGDB - for maize MarpolBase - Genome Database for Marchantia polymorpha Marchantia - for Marchantia CuGenDB - Cucurbit Genomics Database CucCAP – Harnessing genomic resources in cucurbit crops Sol Genomics Network - for Solanaceae   Expression  BAR* CoNekT* CoNekT - diurnal-tools Rice Expression Profile Database (RiceXPro) - for rice Rice Expression Database (RED) - for rice OryzaExpress - for rice   Gene function  The Arabidopsis Information Resource (TAIR) The Rice Annotation Project (RAP) Rice Genome Annotation Project Oryzabase - for rice funRiceGenes - for rice   Nature variation - Rice  RiceVarMap v2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Wenyuan Ruan</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/01_wenyuanruan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/01_wenyuanruan/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Crop Science Mineral nutrition associated shoot architecture and crop yields Mechanisms of mineral nutrition sensing, uptake, translocation, and utilization Crosstalk of mineral nutrition signaling and homeostasis   Education:  2011-2014, PhD in Biochemistry and molecular biology, Zhejiang University 2008-2011, MS in Plant Science, Jilin University 2004-2008, BS in Biological Engineering, Hebei University of Science and Technology   Contact:  Email: ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/links/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/links/tools/</guid>
      <description>GO analysis  agriGOv2 g:Profiler QuickGO REVIGO   KEGG analysis  KOBAS Pathview   Promoter analysis  New PLACE PlantPAN 3.0 PlantCARE   Subcellular localization Prediction  PSI-predictor WoLF PSORT or WoLF PSORT iPSORT cNLS Mapper - Nuclear localization signals (NLSs) SignalP 5.0 - Signal peptide and cleavage sites ChloroP-1.1 - Chloroplast transit peptides and cleavage sites TargetP 2.0 - Mitochondrial, chloroplastic, secretory pathway   Plot  GSDS2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Lei Xu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/02_leixu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/02_leixu/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Regulation mechanisms of root meristem activety in rice Uptake and transport of phosphate   Education:  PhD in Biology, Zhejiang University   Contact:  Email: xuleisy@zju.edu.cn ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/publication/</guid>
      <description>2022  Xu, L., Zhao, H., Wang, J., Wang, X., Jia, X., Xu, Z., Li, R., Jiang, K., Chen, Z., Luo, J., Xie, X., &amp;amp; Yi, K. (2022). AIM1-dependent high basal SA accumulation modulates stomatal aperture in rice (p. 2022.06.23.497111). bioRxiv. [Link]
Guo, M., Zhang, Yuxin, Jia, X., Wang, X., Zhang, Yibo, Liu, J., Yang, Q., Ruan, W., &amp;amp; Yi, K. (2022). Alternative splicing of REGULATOR OF LEAF INCLINATION 1 modulates phosphate starvation signaling and growth in plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Hongyu Zhao</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/03_hongyuzhao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/03_hongyuzhao/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Evo-Devo Molecular Genetics and Evolution Bioinformatics Multi-omics analysis   Education:  PhD in Biology, Zhejiang University   Contact:  Email: ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Long Wang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/04_longwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/04_longwang/</guid>
      <description>Phosphorus is an essential plant nutrient, which participates in all metabolic processes in plants. Due to the easy fixation by soil, nearly 70% of global arable land suffers from Pi deficiency. Thus, farmers have to apply more phosphate fertilizer to guarantee the plant growth and crop yield, which in turn also causes severe eutrophication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/events/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/events/</guid>
      <description>Journal Club Date: 2021-08-27
Presenter: Yibo Zhang
Reference:
Cheng, Mengzhu, Lihong Wang, Qing Zhou, Daiyin Chao, Shingo Nagawa, Ding He, Jiazhi Zhang, et al. Lanthanum(III) Triggers AtrbohD- and Jasmonic Acid-Dependent Systemic Endocytosis in Plants.
Nature Communications 12, no. 1 (December 2021): 4327. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-021-24379-z.
PDF
Presenter: Jichun Wang
Reference:
Song, Shiyong, Ying Chen, Lu Liu, Yanwen Wang, Shengjie Bao, Xuan Zhou, Zhi Wei Norman Teo, Chuanzao Mao, Yinbo Gan, and Hao Yu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Xianqing Jia</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/05_xianqingjia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/05_xianqingjia/</guid>
      <description>Xianqing finished his PhD study at Nanjing University and joined our lab in June 2020. He has board interest in evolution of genomic features accompanied by morphologic changes in plants.
 Research Interests:  Evo-Devo Plant-Microbe interaction Molecular Genetics and Evolution Bioinformatics and Multi-omics analysis   Education:  2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Yanjun Li</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/05_yanjunli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/05_yanjunli/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Regulation mechanisms of Plant and root microbiome interactions   Education:  2018-2022, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University 2015-2018, MS in Botany, Northeast Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/contact/</guid>
      <description>Keke Yi&amp;rsquo;s Lab Institute of Agricultural Resources and Regional Planning (IARRP),
Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences (CAAS)
Address: 12 Zhongguancun Nandajie Street, Haidian District, Beijing, 100081, China
Telephone: +86 010-82108643
Email: yikeke@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yibo Zhang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/06_yibozhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/06_yibozhang/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Calmodulin Green manure Regulation of phosphate homeostasis   Education:  2019 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2015-2018, MSc in Agricultural Resources and environment, Henan Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: utopiazhangyb@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhuang Xu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/07_zhuangxu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/07_zhuangxu/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Cell and Develpment Biology Phosphate utilization and hemostasis in rice Microbiome, colonization of the root microbiome   Education:  2020 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science MSc in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BE in Bioengineering, HuaZhong Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: 631083028@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jiahong Yu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/08_jiahongyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/08_jiahongyu/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Nutrition utilization in vegetables   Education:  2020 - Present, PhD in Agricultural Resources and Environment, Nanjing Agricultural University MSc in Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BSa in Horticultural, South China Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: 809394701@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruili Li</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/09_ruilili/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/09_ruilili/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Mechanisms of phosphate uptake, transport and redistribution in plants   Education:  2021 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science MSc in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BE in Biological Science，Henan Institute of Science and Technology   Contact:  Email: 1748110531@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xuge Lou</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/10_xugelou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/10_xugelou/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Root system development and nutrient absorption in rice   Education:  2022 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2015-2022, ME and BE in Environmental Engineering, Southwest University   Contact:  Email: louxg2021@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Meina Guo</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/alumni/meinaguo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/alumni/meinaguo/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Crop Science Phosphate associated shoot architecture and crop yields Mechanisms of phosphate uptake, translocation, and utilization   Education:  2012-2015, PhD in Biology, Zhejiang University 2009-2012, MS in Plant Science, Jilin University 2005-2009, BS in Plant Science, Inner Mongolia University for the Nationalities   Contact:  Email: ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xueqing Wang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/alumni/xueqingwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/alumni/xueqingwang/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Plant Nutrition Phosphate homeostasis in plants   Education:  2018 - 2022, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2015 - 2018, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Zhejiang Normal University 2011 - 2015, BS in Agricultural Resources and environment, Shandong Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: wangxueqing2011@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yuxin Zhang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/alumni/yuxinzhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/alumni/yuxinzhang/</guid>
      <description>YUXIN ZHANG, a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science, majors in Molecular Biology and Plant Physiology, researching in the signaling pathways of phosphorus in rice.
 Research Interests:  Cell Biology Molecular Biology Plant Physiology signaling pathways of phosphorus   Education:  2019 - 2022, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2014 - 2018, BS in Pratacultural Science, Beijing Forestry University   Contact:  Email: zhangyuxin1402@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations - 2022.06</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/gallery/2022summer/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/gallery/2022summer/gallery/</guid>
      <description>Please accept our best wishes for your bright future!
                                         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jichun Wang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/alumni/jichunwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/alumni/jichunwang/</guid>
      <description>The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
 Research Interests:  Molecular Biology   Education:  2019 - 2022, MSc in Biological Sciences, Zhejiang Normal University   Contact:  Email: ertun930@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 National Congress of Plant Biology (NCPB)</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/gallery/202112ncpb/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/gallery/202112ncpb/gallery/</guid>
      <description>                                                  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yili Zhu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/alumni/yilizhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/alumni/yilizhu/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Cell Biology Molecular Biology Plant Physiology Absorption And Transport Of Phosphorus Rice Root Development   Education:  2018.09 - 2021.06, MSc in Biological Sciences, Zhejiang Normal University   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations - 2021.05</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/gallery/2021summer/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/gallery/2021summer/gallery/</guid>
      <description>Really enjoy the time we spent together. Hope you have a bright future!
                                     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhenhui Guo</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/alumni/zhenhuiguo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/alumni/zhenhuiguo/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Plant Nutrition Phosphate homeostasis in plants   Education:  2020.09 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy University 2017.09 - 2020.06, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science BS in Agricultural Resources and Environment, Henan Agricultural University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chengzhen Huang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/alumni/chengzhenhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/alumni/chengzhenhuang/</guid>
      <description>Current Research Interests:  Heart regeneration   Education:  2020.09 - Present: PhD, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College 2016.09 - 2019.06: MS in Agricultural Resources Utilization, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations - 2018.06</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/gallery/2018summer/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/gallery/2018summer/gallery/</guid>
      <description>                                  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junwen Shao</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/11_junwenshao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/11_junwenshao/</guid>
      <description>The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
 Research Interests:  Molecular Biology   Education:  2020 - Present, MSc in Biological Sciences, Zhejiang Normal University 2016-2020, Bachelor of Biology Science, Huainan Normal University   Contact:  Email: shaojunwen412@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tian Zhou</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/12_tianzhou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/12_tianzhou/</guid>
      <description>Tian Zhou, a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science, majors in Resource Utilization and Plant Protection, researching in the interaction between phosphorus and zinc in rice.
 Research Interests:  Molecular Biology Plant Physiology   Education:  2020 - Present, MSc in Resource Utilization and Plant Protection, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2016 - 2020, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qianqian Zhang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/13_qianqianzhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/13_qianqianzhang/</guid>
      <description>Qianqian Zhang, a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science, majors in Plant Nutrition.
 Research Interests:  Plant Physiology   Education:  2021 - Present, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2017 - 2021, Bachelor of Biology science, Huazhong Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: 1779846422@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suna Ren</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/14_sunaren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/14_sunaren/</guid>
      <description>A graduate student Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Anhui agricultural university
 Research Interests:  Resource utilization Plant protection   Education:  2021 - Present, MSc in Biology, Anhui agricultural university 2017-2021 bachelor of science, Hebei agricultural university   Contact:  Email: rensuna19@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Li Kong</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/15_likong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/15_likong/</guid>
      <description>The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
 Research Interests:  Molecular Biology   Education:  2021 - Present, MSc in Biology, Zhejiang Normal University 2017-2021, Bachelor of Biology Science, Shanxi Normal University   Contact:  Email: 3505421512@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jianhao Ren</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/16_jianhaoren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/16_jianhaoren/</guid>
      <description>Jianhao Ren，a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agriculture Science，majors in Plant Nutrition.
 Research Interests:  Plant Physiology   Education:  2022 - Present, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agriculture Science 2018 - 2022, Bachelor of Resource and Environment Science, South China Agriculture University   Contact:  Email: 1371918092@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plant Cell paper is online now!</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2022tpc/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2022tpc/detail/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Phosphate (Pi) limitation represents a primary constraint on crop production. To better cope with Pi deficiency stress, plants have evolved multiple adaptive mechanisms for phosphorus acquisition and utilization, including the alteration of growth and the activation of Pi starvation signaling. However, how these strategies are coordinated remains largely unknown. Here, we found that the alternative splicing (AS) of REGULATOR OF LEAF INCLINATION 1 (RLI1) in rice (Oryza sativa) produces two protein isoforms: RLI1a, containing MYB DNA binding domain; and RLI1b, containing both MYB and coiled-coil (CC) domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reciprocal inhibitory interplay between phosphate and iron signaling in rice</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2021mp3/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2021mp3/detail/</guid>
      <description>Summary Phosphorous (P) and iron (Fe) are two essential nutrients for plant growth and development and are highly abundant elements in the earth&amp;rsquo;s crust but often display low availability to plants. Due to the ability to form insoluble complexes, the antagonistic interaction between P and Fe nutrition in plants has been noticed for decades. However, the underlying molecular mechanism modulating the signaling and homeostasis between them is still obscure. Here, we show that the possible iron sensors HRZs, iron deficiency induced E3 ligases, could interact with the central regulator for phosphate (Pi) signaling, PHR2, and prompt its ubiquitination at lysine residues K319 and K328, leading to its degradation in rice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights of phosphate transport and signaling in green plants</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2021newp/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2021newp/detail/</guid>
      <description>Summary Phosphorus (P) is an essential element for plant growth and development. Vacuoles play a fundamental role in the storage and remobilization of P in plants, while our understanding of the evolutionary mechanisms of creating and reusing P stores are limited. Besides, we also know very little about the coordination of intercellular P translocation, neither the inorganic phosphate (Pi) signaling nor the Pi transport patterns. Here we summarize recent advances in understanding the core elements involved in cellular and/or subcellular P homeostasis and signaling in unicellular green algae and multicellular land plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unloading phosphate for starch synthesis in cereal grains</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2021mp2/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2021mp2/detail/</guid>
      <description>OsPHO1;2 exports excess Pi from endosperm to maintain proper levels of AGPase activity for starch biosynthesis
During starch biosynthesis in developing endosperm, glucose-1-P and ATP are converted into ADP-glucose and inorganic pyrophosphate (PPi) by ADP-glucose pyrophosphorylase (AGPase). ADP-glucose is used for starch biosynthesis and PPi is hydrolyzed into Pi. The plasma membrane (PM)-localized OsPHO1;2 is expressed in the endosperm cells and exports excess Pi from the developing endosperm to maintain Pi homeostasis for proper levels of AGPase activity and starch biosynthesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plant Cell paper is online now!</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2021tpc/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2021tpc/detail/</guid>
      <description>Summary Both genetic and epigenetic information must be transferred from mother to daughter cells during cell division. The mechanisms through which information about chromatin states and epigenetic marks like histone 3 lysine 27 trimethylation (H3K27me3) are transferred have been characterized in animals; these processes are less well understood in plants. Here, based on characterization of a dwarf rice (Oryza sativa) mutant (dwarf-related wd40 protein 1, drw1) deficient for yeast CTF4 (CHROMOSOME TRANSMISSION FIDELITY PROTEIN 4), we discovered that CTF4 orthologs in plants use common cellular machinery yet accomplish divergent functional outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our MP paper is online now!</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/post/2021mp/detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/post/2021mp/detail/</guid>
      <description>Summary Phosphorus is an essential nutrient for plants. It is stored as inorganic phosphate (Pi) in vacuoles of land plants but as inorganic polyphosphate (polyP) in chlorophyte algae. Although it has been known that the SPX-MFS and VPE proteins are respectively responsible for Pi influx and efflux across the tonoplast in land plants, the mechanisms underlying polyP homeostasis and the transition of phosphorus storage forms during the evolution of green plants remain unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
