<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on YiLab</title>
    <link>https://yilab.life/member/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on YiLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://yilab.life/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Keke Yi</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/00_kekeyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/00_kekeyi/</guid>
      <description>I’m a group leader of soil-plant interaction at the Institute of Agricultural Resources and Regional Planning (IARRP) from the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences (CAAS). My group is working with the molecular mechanism of Pi uptake and homeostasis in plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Wenyuan Ruan</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/01_wenyuanruan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/01_wenyuanruan/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Crop Science Mineral nutrition associated shoot architecture and crop yields Mechanisms of mineral nutrition sensing, uptake, translocation, and utilization Crosstalk of mineral nutrition signaling and homeostasis   Education:  2011-2014, PhD in Biochemistry and molecular biology, Zhejiang University 2008-2011, MS in Plant Science, Jilin University 2004-2008, BS in Biological Engineering, Hebei University of Science and Technology   Contact:  Email: ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Lei Xu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/02_leixu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/02_leixu/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Regulation mechanisms of root meristem activety in rice Uptake and transport of phosphate   Education:  PhD in Biology, Zhejiang University   Contact:  Email: xuleisy@zju.edu.cn ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Hongyu Zhao</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/03_hongyuzhao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/03_hongyuzhao/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Evo-Devo Molecular Genetics and Evolution Bioinformatics Multi-omics analysis   Education:  PhD in Biology, Zhejiang University   Contact:  Email: ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Long Wang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/04_longwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/04_longwang/</guid>
      <description>Phosphorus is an essential plant nutrient, which participates in all metabolic processes in plants. Due to the easy fixation by soil, nearly 70% of global arable land suffers from Pi deficiency. Thus, farmers have to apply more phosphate fertilizer to guarantee the plant growth and crop yield, which in turn also causes severe eutrophication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Xianqing Jia</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/05_xianqingjia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/05_xianqingjia/</guid>
      <description>Xianqing finished his PhD study at Nanjing University and joined our lab in June 2020. He has board interest in evolution of genomic features accompanied by morphologic changes in plants.
 Research Interests:  Evo-Devo Plant-Microbe interaction Molecular Genetics and Evolution Bioinformatics and Multi-omics analysis   Education:  2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Yanjun Li</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/05_yanjunli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/05_yanjunli/</guid>
      <description>                                   Research Interests:  Regulation mechanisms of Plant and root microbiome interactions   Education:  2018-2022, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University 2015-2018, MS in Botany, Northeast Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: ORCID:   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yibo Zhang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/06_yibozhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/06_yibozhang/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Calmodulin Green manure Regulation of phosphate homeostasis   Education:  2019 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2015-2018, MSc in Agricultural Resources and environment, Henan Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: utopiazhangyb@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhuang Xu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/07_zhuangxu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/07_zhuangxu/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Cell and Develpment Biology Phosphate utilization and hemostasis in rice Microbiome, colonization of the root microbiome   Education:  2020 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science MSc in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BE in Bioengineering, HuaZhong Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: 631083028@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jiahong Yu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/08_jiahongyu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/08_jiahongyu/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Nutrition utilization in vegetables   Education:  2020 - Present, PhD in Agricultural Resources and Environment, Nanjing Agricultural University MSc in Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BSa in Horticultural, South China Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: 809394701@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruili Li</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/09_ruilili/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/09_ruilili/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Mechanisms of phosphate uptake, transport and redistribution in plants   Education:  2021 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science MSc in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BE in Biological Science，Henan Institute of Science and Technology   Contact:  Email: 1748110531@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xuge Lou</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/10_xugelou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/10_xugelou/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests:  Root system development and nutrient absorption in rice   Education:  2022 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2015-2022, ME and BE in Environmental Engineering, Southwest University   Contact:  Email: louxg2021@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Junwen Shao</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/11_junwenshao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/11_junwenshao/</guid>
      <description>The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
 Research Interests:  Molecular Biology   Education:  2020 - Present, MSc in Biological Sciences, Zhejiang Normal University 2016-2020, Bachelor of Biology Science, Huainan Normal University   Contact:  Email: shaojunwen412@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tian Zhou</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/12_tianzhou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/12_tianzhou/</guid>
      <description>Tian Zhou, a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science, majors in Resource Utilization and Plant Protection, researching in the interaction between phosphorus and zinc in rice.
 Research Interests:  Molecular Biology Plant Physiology   Education:  2020 - Present, MSc in Resource Utilization and Plant Protection, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2016 - 2020, B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qianqian Zhang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/13_qianqianzhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/13_qianqianzhang/</guid>
      <description>Qianqian Zhang, a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science, majors in Plant Nutrition.
 Research Interests:  Plant Physiology   Education:  2021 - Present, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2017 - 2021, Bachelor of Biology science, Huazhong Agricultural University   Contact:  Email: 1779846422@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suna Ren</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/14_sunaren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/14_sunaren/</guid>
      <description>A graduate student Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Anhui agricultural university
 Research Interests:  Resource utilization Plant protection   Education:  2021 - Present, MSc in Biology, Anhui agricultural university 2017-2021 bachelor of science, Hebei agricultural university   Contact:  Email: rensuna19@163.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Li Kong</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/15_likong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/15_likong/</guid>
      <description>The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
 Research Interests:  Molecular Biology   Education:  2021 - Present, MSc in Biology, Zhejiang Normal University 2017-2021, Bachelor of Biology Science, Shanxi Normal University   Contact:  Email: 3505421512@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jianhao Ren</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/16_jianhaoren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/16_jianhaoren/</guid>
      <description>Jianhao Ren，a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agriculture Science，majors in Plant Nutrition.
 Research Interests:  Plant Physiology   Education:  2022 - Present, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agriculture Science 2018 - 2022, Bachelor of Resource and Environment Science, South China Agriculture University   Contact:  Email: 1371918092@qq.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
