<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on YiLab</title>
    <link>https://yilab.life/member/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on YiLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://yilab.life/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Keke Yi</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/00_kekeyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/00_kekeyi/</guid>
      <description>I’m a group leader of soil-plant interaction at the Institute of Agricultural Resources and Regional Planning (IARRP) from the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences (CAAS). My group is working with the molecular mechanism of Pi uptake and homeostasis in plants. We are also interested with how the plants sense the external nutrition availability to modulate growth.
Research Interests: Function and Evolution of Phosphate Transporter Plant nutritions Cell and Develpment Biology Education: 2005/10 - 2008/10, PhD in Cell and Develpment Biology, John Innes Centre / University of East Anglia 1997/09 - 2000/07, MS in Plant Science, Zhejiang University 1993/09 - 1997/07, BS in Plant Science, Zhejiang University Contact: Email: yikeke@gmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Wenyuan Ruan</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/01_wenyuanruan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/01_wenyuanruan/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Crop Science Mineral nutrition associated shoot architecture and crop yields Mechanisms of mineral nutrition sensing, uptake, translocation, and utilization Crosstalk of mineral nutrition signaling and homeostasis Education: 2011-2014, PhD in Biochemistry and molecular biology, Zhejiang University 2008-2011, MS in Plant Science, Jilin University 2004-2008, BS in Biological Engineering, Hebei University of Science and Technology Contact: Email: ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Lei Xu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/02_leixu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/02_leixu/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Regulation mechanisms of root meristem activety in rice Uptake and transport of phosphate Education: PhD in Biology, Zhejiang University Contact: Email: xuleisy@zju.edu.cn ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jia Wang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/20_jiawang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/20_jiawang/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Regulation mechanism of Pi signaling and Pi homeostasis in plant Education: PhD in Genetics, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences MS in Omics, University of Southern Denmark Contact: Email: wangjiasdc@gmail.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Yanjun Li</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/05_yanjunli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/05_yanjunli/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Regulation mechanisms of Plant and root microbiome interactions Education: 2018-2022, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Fujian Agriculture and Forestry University 2015-2018, MS in Botany, Northeast Agricultural University Contact: Email: ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhuang Xu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/07_zhuangxu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/07_zhuangxu/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Cell and Develpment Biology Phosphate utilization and hemostasis in rice Microbiome, colonization of the root microbiome Education: 2020 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science MSc in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BE in Bioengineering, HuaZhong Agricultural University Contact: Email: 631083028@qq.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruili Li</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/09_ruilili/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/09_ruilili/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Mechanisms of phosphate uptake, transport and redistribution in plants Education: 2021 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science MSc in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Zhejiang Normal University BE in Biological Science，Henan Institute of Science and Technology Contact: Email: 1748110531@qq.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xuge Lou</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/10_xugelou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/10_xugelou/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Root system development and nutrient absorption in rice Education: 2022 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2015-2022, ME and BE in Environmental Engineering, Southwest University Contact: Email: louxg2021@163.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jinyu Zheng</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/17_jinyuzheng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/17_jinyuzheng/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Rice root development and its interaction with soil Education: 2023 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science ME in Bioengineering, Shaanxi Normal University BE in Bioengineering, Northwest A&amp;amp;F University Contact: Email: 2569622282@qq.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tianjie Li</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/19_tianjieli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/19_tianjieli/</guid>
      <description> Research Interests: Efficient utilization of Phosphorus and Iron nutrients in crops; Genetic improvement of plant nutrition Education: 2024 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science MSc in Horticulture, Tianjin Agricultural University BE in Landscape Architecture, Tianjin Agricultural University Contact: Email: ltj310342@126com ORCID: https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0130-6621 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chenxi Lu</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/21_chenxilu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/21_chenxilu/</guid>
      <description> The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
Research Interests: Root system development and nutrient absorption in rice Education: 2024 - Present, PhD in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences 2021 - 2024, MSc in Environmental Science, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences 2017 - 2021, BE in Environmental Science, Nankai University Contact: Email: luchenxi_0107@163.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qianqian Zhang</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/13_qianqianzhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/13_qianqianzhang/</guid>
      <description> Qianqian Zhang, a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science, majors in Plant Nutrition.
Research Interests: Plant Physiology Education: 2021 - Present, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Science 2017 - 2021, Bachelor of Biology science, Huazhong Agricultural University Contact: Email: 1779846422@qq.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Li Kong</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/15_likong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/15_likong/</guid>
      <description> The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
Research Interests: Molecular Biology Education: 2021 - Present, MSc in Biology, Zhejiang Normal University 2017-2021, Bachelor of Biology Science, Shanxi Normal University Contact: Email: 3505421512@qq.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jianhao Ren</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/16_jianhaoren/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/16_jianhaoren/</guid>
      <description> Jianhao Ren，a graduate student from Chinese Academy of Agriculture Science，majors in Plant Nutrition.
Research Interests: Plant Physiology Education: 2022 - Present, MSc in Plant Nutrition, Chinese Academy of Agriculture Science 2018 - 2022, Bachelor of Resource and Environment Science, South China Agriculture University Contact: Email: 1371918092@qq.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fan Shi</title>
      <link>https://yilab.life/member/18_fanshi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yilab.life/member/18_fanshi/</guid>
      <description> The Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences and Zhejiang Normal University jointly trained graduate student
Research Interests: Molecular Biology Education: 2022- Present, MSc in Biology, Zhejiang Normal University 2018-2022, Bachelor of Biology Science, YuLin University Contact: Email: 1425389698@qq.com ORCID: </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
